Guide to the Jerome Ziegler papers, 1955-2011.
Ziegler, Jerome papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Jerome Ziegler papers, 1955-2011.
23-26-4018
Ziegler, Jerome M.
10.1 cubic feet.
Correspondence, publications, research material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, reports, publications, research files, course material, and talks pertaining to his teaching career in the New York State College of Human Ecology, his work directing leadership seminars, and his research on education reform and race relations.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Ziegler was dean of the College of Human Ecology from 1978-1988 and then taught in the Dept. of Policy Analysis and Management and in the Cornell Institute for Public Affairs (CIPA) from 2002-2011. His work as a researcher focused on urban development, working as a consultant in education and race relations for numerous public and private agencies. In 1995 he founded the Leadership Institute for School Principals, a professional education program for school leaders.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, reports, publications, research files, course material, and talks pertaining to his teaching career in the New York State College of Human Ecology, his work directing leadership seminars, and his research on education reform and race relations.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ziegler, Jerome M.; Cornell University -- Faculty; Leadership Institute for School Principals.; New York State College of Human Ecology. Department of Policy Analysis and Management.
Subjects:
School principals -- In-service training.; Educational leadership.; Educational change -- United States.; School principals -- United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Collection is closed for processing.
SERIES LIST
Series I: Biographical
Series II: Publications
Series III: Talks
Series IV: Course Material
Series V: Seminars
Series VI: Reference/Resource Files
Series VII: Correspondence
Series VIII: Interviews
Series IX: Calendars and Job Corps Files
Series X: Warren Ziegler Files (Jerome Ziegler's Brother)
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical
  - Biographical information, 1972-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II. Publications
  - Bibliographies, 1945-1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Book Notes, 1969-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The Journey from Chungking to Wuhan", no date (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1960-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "The Question of Educational Disparities in America Issues for the Urban Coalition to Consider", no date (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Store Front Schools and Street Camps", no date (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Let's Run 50 Peace Candidates", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The Role of Special Curricula - Black Studies in the Liberal Arts", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "What Does Quality Education Mean?", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Some Questions Before Us: Notes Toward the Future in Higher Education", 1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "The Community College" Big Government Handout or Key to the Future?", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Education Today and Tomorrow", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Book Outline - Curriculum for 21st Century, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Potential Impact of Federal Procurement Set-Aside Policy in Urban Areas" - prepared for the Urban Regional Task Force, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Will We Have a National Urban Policy?", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Preparation of Students for 1980 and Beyond", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "The Future of the City", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Notes on the Revolutions of our Times - Thinking about the 1980s", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "The Research Agenda for the '80s - Social Sciences", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Barriers to Full Employment of Rural Youth", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "International Education Review" - wrote a review and wrote summary of "Results of a Survey of Global/International Education Activity in Pennsylvania Colleges and Universities", 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "The College and the City", Fall 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Prospectus for a book about Why People Become Academics- includes interview with Milton Rakove, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "A human Ecology Approach to Troubled Youth and Their Families", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "A Human Ecology Approach to Aging", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Work, Employment, Leisure: Policies for a New Era", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - ""Stray Comments by a Sometime Observer of the British Scene", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Comments of the document "Challenge of Education, A Policy Perspective" - by the Ministry of Education, Government of India, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - India Diary, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - China Journal, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Winds of Change", 1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Talking with Kids About Aids", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Introduction for "Affluent Society", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Education: The Crucial Variable for Children?", 1992 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Rethinking American Urban Policy", 1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Ecology Versus Economic Development - A Problem in Education" - International Conference in Bulgaria, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Op Ed Page - New York Times, 1993-01 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Education: The Crucial Variable for Children", 1983 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Can High Schools Foster Youth Development?", 2002 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Series III. Talks
  - Speech Material, no date (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Outline of Lecture on Values, 1972-1993 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Open University Conference, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Conference on Post-Secondary Occupational Education, 1973-10-03 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Pennsylvania Association of College and Universities, 1973-10 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Leadership Policy Talks, no date (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Pennsylvania State College Institute - "The Missions of the State Colleges", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Conference of Black Educators, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Adult Education Conference Dinner, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Delaware Community College, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Cooper Union Forum, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Address to CICU, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Commencement - East Stroudsburg State College, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Teacher Education Conference - Lockhaven College, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Teacher Education Conference - Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Conference of Pennsylvania Graduate Deans, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Testimony at Senate Education Committee Hearing on the Open College, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Philadelphia Community College Commencement, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Commencement Westchester State College, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Cooper Union - "The Future of Higher Education", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Pennsylvania Art Education Association, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Pennsylvania State Colleges and Universities - Vice Presidents and Deans, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Task Force on Life Long Learning, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Education Commission of the States Seminar, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Educational Congress of Northeast Pennsylvania, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - East Stroudsburg, Pennsylvania, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Maryland Association for Higher Education, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Cooper Union - "Does the Family Have a Future?", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - "Education for the 21st Century", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Faculty Meeting, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Testimony before the Senate Committee on Labor and Human Resources, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Administrators of Home Economics - Annual Meeting, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Remarks to Faculty, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Buffalo Club of Cornell Women, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Erie County 4-H Leaders, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Division of Campus Life, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Advisory Council - "Planning for the 1980s", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Tompkins County Community College, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Alumni Breakfast, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - "the College and the City", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Student Welcome, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Remarks to the Faculty, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Rochester Youth Workers, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Sage Chapel - "Purpose of Education/Fallacy of Self", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Alumni Breakfast, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - NYSAEHE, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Student Welcome, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Remarks to Faculty, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Cornell Graduation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Speeches to Cornell Alumni, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - New York State Assembly - Committee on Higher Education, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Oregon Alumni - "Does the City Have a Future?", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - United Way, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Southeastern Massachusetts University - Commencement, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Student Welcome, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Broome Community College, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 4-H Conference, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - New York City "Future of the City", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Extension Club, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Remarks to County Coordinators, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Purposes of Education and Fallacy of Self", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Student Welcome, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Remarks to Faculty, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Human Service Studies Graduate Seminar "Is Social Planning Possible?", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Potsdam Symposium, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Future of Cities", 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Welcome to Students, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Human Service Studies Graduate Seminar "Is Social Planning Possible?", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Potsdam Symposium, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Future of Cities", 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Welcome to Students, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Challenge of Education - Ministry of Education, India, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Can Extension Serve Metropolitan/Urban Areas?", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Changing Nature of Work" - San Francisco Symposium, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Sage Chapel Sermon - "Race and Culture in 2001", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Welcome to Students, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - SUNY Plattsburgh, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 4-H Conference, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - NASULGC Centennial Symposium, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Future of Family Policy, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Gamma Sigma Delta, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Kaufman Interview, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Alumni Breakfast, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Extension Conference, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Wayne State University, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Cooperative Extension Services North Central Region Urban Conference, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Auburn Graduation, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - International Conference on Ecology and Industry - Bulgaria, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "School Reform - Does it Work?", 1996 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Educational Policy Lecture, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Empire College Talk, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Kazakhstan Conference Lecture, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Cornell Institute for Public Affairs Colloquium, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "Mr. Dooley and the Great Square of Pegasus", no date (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Series IV. Course Material
  - Philosophy of Education - Hempstead Cooperative College Center, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Urb 416 - Spring, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - College for Human Services - Humanities Program, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Future of the City Seminar, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - HSS 202 - Urban Scene, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Human Ecology Seminars, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Environmental Seminar, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Harvard Project on Schooling and Children, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - New Course, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - CSE 601, no date (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - HSS 464, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Course on "The City", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Course on "The City" - articles, 1960-1970 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - HSS 600, 1977-1982 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - HSS 600, 1982 Fall (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - HSS 600, 1989 - Fall (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - HSS 600, 1990; 1992 - Fall (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - HSS 601, 1980s; 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Bill Rosen's Class, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - HSS 658, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - HSS 658- - Ethics Cases, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - HSS 658, 1990 Spring (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - HSS 658 - Ethics and Public Policy, 1991 Fall (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - HSS 658 - Bio Medical Issues, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - HSS 658, 1993 Fall (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - HSS 658 - Sessions VII and IX, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - HSS 658 - Sessions XII, XIV, XX, XXI, XII, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - HSS 658, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - HSS 664, 1978-1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - HSS 664, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - HSS 664, 1991-1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - HSS 664, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - HSS 664 - Sessions 20 and 22 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - HSS 664 - Race (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - HSS 458 - Ethics, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ethics - Antigone, 1997 Spring; 1998 Fall; 2007 Fall (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - PAM 230, 1997 Fall (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - PAM 600 - Abuse of Power, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - PAM 600 - Nature of Power, 2004-2009 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - PAM 631 - Ethics and Public Policy - Cloning, 1998 Fall (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - PAM 631 - Sessions II, V and VI, 1998-2007 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - PAM 631 - Sessions IV and VII, 1998-2007 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - PAM 631 - Sessions IX, XIII, XIV, XV, XI, 1998-2007 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - PAM 631 - Sessions XV, XII, XIII, XVI, XXIII, XIV, 1998-2007 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - PAM 631 - Ethics, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - PAM 631 - Ethics Syllabus, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - PAM 631 - Lecture - Education Reform, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - PAM 631 - Bibliography and Syllabus, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - PAM 631 - Material for Sessions, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PAM 631 - Sessions I and II, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PAM 631 - Sessions VIII and IX, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - PAM 631 - Sessions X, XI and XII, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - PAM 631 - Sessions XIII, XIV, XV, XVI, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - PAM 631 - Ethics and Public Policy, 2007 Fall (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - PAM 631 - Nature and Political Leadership, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - PAM 632, 2001-2005 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - PAM 632, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - PAM 632 - Syllabi, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - PAM 632 - Nature of Power Seminar, 2008 Fall (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - PAM 632, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - PAM 632 - Budget, 2007 Spring (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - PAM 632 - Budget Material, Various Dates (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - PAM 632 - Various Sessions, Various Dates (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - PAM 632 - Marbury vs. Madison, no date (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - PAM 632 - Session V (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - PAM 632 - Sessions V and VI (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - PAM 632 - Sessions VIII and IX (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - PAM 632 - Sessions VIII and Various Other Sessions (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - PAM 632 - Session IX (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - PAM 632 - Session IX (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - PAM 632 - Session X (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - PAM 632 - Sessions XI and XII (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - PAM 632 - Session XIII (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - PAM 632 - Sessions XVI - XXVII, 2001-2005 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - PAM 632 - Various Sessions (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - PAM 634 - Wealth of Nations, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - PAM 634, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - PAM 634 - Biomedical Revolution - Session I, 2002 Spring (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - PAM 634 - Biomedical Revolution - Sessions II and III, 2002 Spring (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - PAM 634 - Biomedical Revolution - Sessions V - VII, 2002 Spring (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - PAM 634 - Sessions IX - XIII, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - HD 456, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - CIPA, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series V. Seminars
  - Bryn Mawr Seminar, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Leadership at Kellogg, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - National Executive Service Corps in New York City, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - National Executive Service Corps in New York City, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - National Executive Service Corps - Packet of Readings, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - National Executive Service Corps in New York City, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - National Executive Service Corps in New York City, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Liberating Our Ministries: New Paradigms For the Future" - A Workshop and Team Approach for Congregational Change, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Boston Public Schools, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Leadership Seminar - Principals - Schenectady County, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Schenectady Principals Program, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Syllabi - Principals Leadership Program, 1993-1998 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Leadership Seminars for School Principals - National Executive Service Coprs (NESC) Program Evaluation, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Leadership Seminar - Washington, D.C., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Leadership Seminar - Washington, D.C., 1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Leadership Seminars - New York City and District of Columbia, 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Leadership Seminar - District of Columbia, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Participants List - Philadelphia, 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Leadership Seminar - Principals - Philadelphia District, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Leadership Seminar - Principals - Philadelphia District, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Leadership Seminar - Principals - Philadelphia District, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Leadership Seminar for School Principals and Staff - Readings, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Leadership Seminars - Philadelphia - Includes Packet of Readings - Group II, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Leadership Seminar - Principals Philadelphia District, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Leadership Seminar - Principals Philadelphia District, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Advanced Leadership Seminar - Principals Philadelphia District, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Pastors Session on Families, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Leadership Seminar - Ithaca School District, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Leadership Seminar for Pastors - Geneva Presbytery, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Leadership Seminar - Geneva Presbytery Pastors - Evaluation, 1999-07 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Hudson River Presbytery, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Leadership Development Program - Hudson River Presbytery - Assessment Report, 2000 Summer (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Hudson River Presbytery - Systems Theory, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Leadership Development - Hudson River Presbytery - Various Sessions, 2000-2005 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Executive Service Corps of Delaware Valley, 2000-10 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Leadership Seminar - Albany Presbytery, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Leadership Seminar for Executives of Non-Profits, 2002-1003 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Youth Development Seminar, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - CIPA Colloquium, 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Compulsory School Learning Age Project, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Wilson Center Proposal, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Wales Leadership Seminar correspondence and memos, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 16-20)
  - Wales Seminar syllabi, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 21-22)
  - Juvenile Justice Project, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Leadership Seminar - New Wales Audit Office, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Leadership Seminar, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Research Proposal on the Progress of School Reform in New York State, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Senior Citizens "Soul of America" Seminar, 2002-1008 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Senior Citizen Seminar - Session III, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Senior Citizens Seminar - The Nature, Sources and Use of Power, 2005 Spring (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Senior Citizens Seminar - Immigration, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Senior Citizens Seminars, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Seminar on Russian Literature and Culture, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Duke University Seminar, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Duke University Seminar, 2007 March (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - CIPA Colloquium, 2007-2008 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tutorial - Nature of Power, 1998 Spring; 2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tutorial/Seminar, 2008 Spring (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Tutorial/Seminar - Readings, 2008-2009 Fall (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Series VI. Reference/Resource Files
  - Peace/War, 1946-1960 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - U.S.S.R., 1950-1959 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Articles, papers on college and general education theory, 1955-1969 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Education Disparities Task Force, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - City - Henry Cohen's Papers, 1970-1979 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Barrel City, 1974-1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Barrel City, 1972-2004 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Learning Stance Project - Warren Ziegler Director, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Learning Stance Project, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Human Ecology 10th Anniversary Symposium, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Brazil, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Study Leave Notes, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Work and Race: The Problem of Urban Development, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Articles, papers for Sage Sermon, 1987-05-17 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Policies for the 90s, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Race, Poverty, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Multicultural/Mainstream - The Common Good, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Mental Health Services, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Corporation for National Service, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 22-23)
  - Articles and notes on cloning, 1997-2006 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Articles and notes for senior citizens seminar, 1999, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Articles and notes "Lenses on the Human Condition Through Plays", 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Advancing the Youth Development Agenda in New York State, 2001-07 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Steve Hamilton - Book Chapter, 2001-2001 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Education and Bush Budget Policies, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Charter Schools, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Guantanamo, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Iraq, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Dropout Summit, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
  - Education Reform, 2001-2006 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - "An Investigation into the Feasibility of Raising the School-leaving Age in New York State", 2005 March (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Education Reform Project, 2009-2010 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Observations - Rochester District, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Series VII. Correspondence
  - General Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1990-01-1990-08 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1990-09-1990-12 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, 1986-1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 2001-2008 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Japan, 1984-1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Highlander Research and Education Center, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Huddersfield University, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Beginning with Children Foundation, 1994-2005 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - China, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - China, 1985-1988 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - China, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - China Trip, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - China Project, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - China Project, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Kazakhstan Conference, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 20)